The entertainment that loves a lot, and lives a lot,
and gives and gives and gives a lot.
The Little Prince is a science fiction, fantasy,
family film directed by Stanley Donen.
After a pilot is forced to make an emergency landing in the Sahara Desert, he befriends a young prince from outer
space; the friendship conjures up stories of journeys through the solar system for the stranded aviator.
The Little Prince, played by Steven Warner.
The Pilot, played by Richard Kiley.
The Snake, played by Bob Fosse.
The Fox, played by Gene Wilder.
The Rose, played by Donna McKechnie.
The King, played by Joss Ackland.
The Little Prince is a 1974 sci-fi fantasy-musical film with screenplay and lyrics by Alan Jay
Lerner, music by Frederick Loewe, arranged and orchestrated by Angela Morley.
It was both directed and produced by Stanley Donen and based on the 1943 classic children-adult's novella, The Little Prince (Le Petit Prince), by the writer, poet
and aviator Count Antoine de Saint-Exupéry, who disappeared near the end of the Second World War some 15 months after his fable was first published.
It was nominated for Academy Awards for Best Song Score and Best Original Song.
The film explores themes of prince, pilot, musical, little boy, planet.
The tone is thought_provoking.